In the first lesson,
在第一课中
you saw some best planning algorithms,
大家看到了一些最佳规划算法
which solve the motion planning problem.
这些算法解决了运动规划问题
But we never formally defined that problem. I'd like to do that now.
但是 我们从未正式定义什么是 “运动规划问题” 而接下来我将定义它
Now, there is a word that you might encounter quite a bit
从现在开始 如果你开始阅读与运动规划算法相关的材料
if you start reading material regarding motion planning algorithm.
那么 大家可能会多次遇到一个词
That word is "configuration space," which defines
那个词就是 “配置空间”
all the possible configurations of a robot in the given world.
它在给定的世界中定义了一个机器人所有的可能配置
Consider the maze word you saw in the first lesson where these words were all 2D grids,
大家想一下在第一节课中看到的迷宫 在那里配置空间都是2D格子
the robot configuration was sometimes two
机器人配置有时候是2维的
dimensional when we presented it as an x_y point,
比如当我们使用 x_y 点来表示它时
and sometimes three dimensional when also including the robot's heading.
有时候是三维的 第三维表示它的前进方向
In fact, the configuration space for vehicle that can become
事实上 我们为车辆所使用的配置空间有可能变得很大
even larger depending on what motion planning algorithms we decide to use.
取决于我们决定使用什么运动规划算法
With this idea of configuration space in mind,
现在我们有了配置空间的概念
we can define a motion planning problem as follows.
下面我们可以定义一个运动规划问题
We're given three things.
这里有3样东西
An initial configuration, a goal configuration
一个是最初配置 另一个是目标配置
and also some constraints describing how the vehicle was allowed to move,
还有一些约束 这些约束描述了车辆能或不能做哪些移动操作
its dynamics and the description of the environment.
车辆的动力学 以及环境描述
Here, it is important to understand how this connects to
这里 重要的是去理解这些配置如何与
the other decision-making modules that you have recently learned about.
其他决策生成模块相关联
Usually, the start configuration is the current configuration of the car given to us by
通常 开始配置是车辆的当前配置
the localization value and the sensors that give us information about car location,
配置值通过定位模块和传感器获取
speed, acceleration they can go, etcetera.
包括车辆位置 速度 加速度等信息
The behavior layer gives us a desired end configuration,
行为层会给我们一个期望的最终配置
and maybe some constraints regarding where to go and at which speed.
也可能会给出一些限制 比如以什么速度去到什么地方
Finally, the prediction completes this problem by giving us
最后 预测模块解决整个运动规划问题 该模块会给我们
information about how the obstacle region will evolve in time.
有关障碍区域如何随着时间演进的信息
This way, the sequence of actions that we generate takes
这样 我们生成的动作序列就会把
into account other vehicles and pedestrian actions.
其他车辆和行人的动作纳入考量
And if we're working with a more sophisticated prediction module,
并且 如果我们使用一个更加先进的预测模块
how our actions might influence them.
那么 我们的行为可能会影响周围对象的行为
The motion planning problem can then be
因此 运动规划问题可以被定义为
defined as final sequence of feasible movements in
在配置空间中最终的一系列可行的运动
the configuration space that's moved the robot from
这些运动将驱动机器人
a start configuration to an end configuration without hitting any obstacles.
从开始配置移动到目标配置 过程中会绕开障碍物
Now, I'm going to ask you to think about configuration spaces in the following questions.
现在 我会问大家几个问题 帮助大家去思考配置空间